<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Development | Wejoinin Blog]]></title>
  <link href="https://blog.wejoinin.com/blog/categories/development/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://blog.wejoinin.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-07T21:07:46-08:00</updated>
  <id>https://blog.wejoinin.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Porkbuns Initiative]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Now With Signup Comments!]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.wejoinin.com/2009/01/30/now-with-signup-comments/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-30T17:26:11-08:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.wejoinin.com/2009/01/30/now-with-signup-comments</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the longest time people have been wondering &ldquo;how can I add a little info to my signup?&rdquo; Potluck signups want to brag about their world-famous chili, and sometimes you just want to express how <em>pumped</em> you are for the upcoming fundraiser. Look no further: we&rsquo;ve added a comment field to the signup process.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2009-01-31-now-with-signup-comments/wejoinin-now-with-comments.gif" alt="Signup… with a comment!" /></p>

<p>Team Wejoinin wrestled long and hard over how best to allow you guys  to provide some extra info on the signup sheet while keeping it simple enough that even my mom could use it. (Hi Mom!) After some thought, we ended up going with a free-form comment box, and sheet authors can just use the sheet description if there are any specific needs for the comment box. (So now you lovely pot-luckers, ask people to describe what they&rsquo;re bringing in the signup comment and all should be well!)</p>

<p>And finally, thanks for all the feedback guys! We can&rsquo;t read minds all to well, so we love hearing your raves and gripes!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New features released this week!]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.wejoinin.com/2008/11/06/new-features-released-this-week/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-06T13:20:25-08:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.wejoinin.com/2008/11/06/new-features-released-this-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone, I&rsquo;m excited to introduce a couple of new features we&rsquo;ve released this week for you all:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Public sheet list views &amp; custom usernames</p></li>
<li><p>Collapsible sheet sidebars</p></li>
<li><p>Redesigned sheet list home</p></li>
<li><p>New sheet administration options: copy &amp; clear</p></li>
<li><p>Sleeker cell header editing</p></li>
</ul>


<h3>Public sheet list views &amp; custom usernames</h3>

<p>Many sheet creators have requested a way to get people to view a grand, big list of their sheets, all in one place. For example, we&rsquo;ve had requests from professors who want their students to see all of their office hour signup sheets in one place. We&rsquo;ve responded by giving you public sheet lists and custom usernames in your URLs.</p>

<p>How does this work? First, <strong>every user receives an autogenerated custom URL</strong> You can see what it is by logging in and checking the URL location bar in your browser.</p>

<p><a href="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/sheet_list_home1.PNG"><img src="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/sheet_list_home1.thumbnail.PNG" alt="sheet_list_home1.PNG" /></a></p>

<p>A close-up of my location bar:</p>

<p><img src="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/custom_url.PNG" alt="custom_url.PNG" /></p>

<p>Tell all your users to go to this URL, and they&rsquo;ll see a special publicly-visible view of all your sheets:</p>

<p><a href="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/public_sheet_list_view1.PNG"><img src="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/public_sheet_list_view1.thumbnail.PNG" alt="public_sheet_list_view1.PNG" /></a></p>

<p>Of course, if you don&rsquo;t want users to see this list of sheets, you&rsquo;re under no obligation to give out your link. (And yes, we&rsquo;re thinking about building in privacy features so you can choose not to display certain sheets in this view!).</p>

<p>If you want to change your username, you can visit the &ldquo;Account&rdquo; tab and change it:</p>

<p><img src="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/account_username_change.PNG" alt="account_username_change.PNG" /></p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Collapsible sheet sidebars</h3>

<p>Many of you have very, very wide sheets that just don&rsquo;t quite seem to fit on a single page. We&rsquo;ve given you the option to collapse that right sidebar&mdash;goodbye, pesky boxes! Ah, now to stretch our legs&hellip;</p>

<p><a href="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/pre_collapse_highlight1.PNG"><img src="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/pre_collapse_highlight1.thumbnail.PNG" alt="pre_collapse_highlight1.PNG" /></a></p>

<p><a href="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/post_collapse1.PNG"><img src="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/post_collapse1.thumbnail.PNG" alt="post_collapse1.PNG" /></a></p>

<h3>Redesigned sheet list home</h3>

<p>We&rsquo;ve rearranged the look and feel of the buttons on the sheets on the front page, to give some more space for sheet descriptions, and also make some more room for current and future feature releases!</p>

<p><a href="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/sheet_list_home1.PNG"><img src="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/sheet_list_home1.thumbnail.PNG" alt="sheet_list_home1.PNG" /></a></p>

<h3>New sheet administration options: copy &amp; clear</h3>

<p>We&rsquo;ve added the ability for you to copy &amp; clear sheets: take a look!</p>

<p><img src="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/admin_tab.PNG" alt="admin_tab.PNG" /></p>

<p>By <strong>making a copy</strong> of a sheet, you&rsquo;ve made a structural copy of your current sheet for future editing. We can see this particularly useful for those of you who use the same signup sheet for repeating events.</p>

<p>By <strong>clearing a sheet</strong>, you remove all signups from a sheet, keeping all the signup slots. This can be particularly useful if you want to reset or reuse a sheet for another time.</p>

<h3>Sleeker cell header editing</h3>

<p>Finally, we&rsquo;ve made cell editing a whole lot sleeker. You&rsquo;ve now got a lot more room to type out what you need, without the clutter of the previous interface.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/edit_col_header.PNG" alt="edit_col_header.PNG" /></p>

<p><img src="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/edit_row_header.PNG" alt="edit_row_header.PNG" /></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re really excited to hear what you think! If you run into any problems or have any questions or comments, please email <a href="mailto:andrew@wejoinin.com">Andrew</a> or <a href="mailto:hsiufan@wejoinin.com">Hsiu-Fan</a> with what you think!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thanks for your feedback!]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.wejoinin.com/2008/09/29/thanks-for-your-feedback/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-29T16:34:28-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.wejoinin.com/2008/09/29/thanks-for-your-feedback</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lately, Hsiu-Fan, Jason and I have been getting lots of emails from our users telling us things from &ldquo;I think your site is awesome!&rdquo; to &ldquo;Something totally broke!&rdquo; We love it!</p>

<p>While it&rsquo;s no secret that fixing broken things is nothing to cheer about, I&rsquo;ve been surprised in the past couple of months at just how much I love having interactions with you all. I love that what we do makes a difference in your lives. I love that you care enough to tell us why something isn&rsquo;t working. Many of you even offer us suggestions to make Wejoinin a little friendlier, and we certainly do take everything into serious consideration.</p>

<p>Hsiu-Fan and I get the warm fuzzies when we get small compliments from &ldquo;this is really useful&rdquo; to big ones like &ldquo;thanks, you guys seriously saved my life!&rdquo; Well, shucks.</p>

<p>This is also to encourage you to email us (<a href="&#109;&#x61;&#105;&#x6c;&#116;&#x6f;&#x3a;&#97;&#x6e;&#100;&#114;&#101;&#119;&#x40;&#119;&#101;&#106;&#x6f;&#105;&#110;&#x69;&#110;&#x2e;&#99;&#111;&#x6d;">&#x61;&#x6e;&#x64;&#x72;&#101;&#119;&#64;&#x77;&#x65;&#x6a;&#111;&#105;&#x6e;&#x69;&#110;&#46;&#x63;&#111;&#x6d;</a> / <a href="&#109;&#x61;&#105;&#x6c;&#x74;&#111;&#58;&#x68;&#x73;&#105;&#117;&#x66;&#97;&#x6e;&#64;&#x77;&#x65;&#106;&#x6f;&#105;&#x6e;&#105;&#x6e;&#x2e;&#99;&#111;&#109;">&#104;&#115;&#105;&#x75;&#102;&#x61;&#x6e;&#x40;&#119;&#101;&#x6a;&#111;&#x69;&#x6e;&#105;&#110;&#x2e;&#x63;&#x6f;&#109;</a>) should you find something really wonky or if you&rsquo;re discovering weird behavior on your sheet or if our sheets are being terribly confusing to you (we&rsquo;ll do our best to make them behave).</p>

<p>Once again, a warm and hearty &ldquo;thanks!&rdquo; from your friends here at Wejoinin,
-Andrew</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed Stuff. Things Better.]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.wejoinin.com/2008/08/24/fixed-stuff-things-better/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-24T18:11:49-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.wejoinin.com/2008/08/24/fixed-stuff-things-better</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Andrew always promises cool new things (sometimes soon), but today I want to tell you about cool things that are no longer broken.</p>

<p>For awhile now, editing sheets has been finicky to downright broken in IE. I updated the site a few days ago, after fixing it a week ago and waiting awhile to make sure it really didn&rsquo;t break anything else that was important. There were two things that were broken: deleting headers (that is, rows and columns), and changing the number of signups allowed on a slot.Warning: tech nerdery ahead. Read on for the gritty details.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>First off, deleting headers. We have a cool Javascript thing that I threw together to deal with the AJAX interactions inside of tooltips and lightboxes, and for the longest time I thought there was an IE bug in there, but it turns out the problem was more mundane. The submit button was a simple <button>Delete</button>, which for most browsers has an implicit type of &ldquo;submit&rdquo;, while IE understands the type to be &ldquo;button&rdquo;, AKA do nothing. We actually have lots of helpers to generate buttons, but in this case, this button was encoded as raw HTML. Easy fix, hard problem to finally track down. (I swear I spent months on this on and off.)</p>

<p>Next up, editing signup sheet cells. I&rsquo;m going to give you a brief sketch the offending code, and what I changed, because I feel like an idiot for this bug being there. I&rsquo;m not sure why it worked at all in the first place, but whatever. There is a div that is cleared, and then an AJAX request is fired off with the form (that was contained inside the div) fields' data. Now we save the serialized form fields, clear the form, and submit the data. Somehow every other browser managed to serialize the non-existant form just fine. Crazy.</p>

<p>PS: I&rsquo;m sharing all this because I feel bad about how broken things are, and kind of want to give you, dear reader, a feel for what kind of stuff is going on here at the red-house-that-is-Wejoinin.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting started (again) and getting excited]]></title>
    <link href="https://blog.wejoinin.com/2008/04/21/getting-started-again-and-getting-excited/"/>
    <updated>2008-04-21T10:11:48-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://blog.wejoinin.com/2008/04/21/getting-started-again-and-getting-excited</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>All&rsquo;s been quiet here among us at Wejoinin for the past couple months or so. Hsiu-Fan and I have been cranking away in our respective classes and haven&rsquo;t quite gotten the time to get in some work on this application.</p>

<p>However, we&rsquo;re <em>really</em> thankful to those of you who use this site and continue to inform us of broken things and give us suggestions and even tell your friends!</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve <a href="http://blog.andrewhao.com/2008/03/11/could-i-be-an-entrepreneur/">written a little bit about how I&rsquo;m taking an entrepreneurship class</a> here at UC Berkeley in the <a href="http://cet.berkeley.edu">Center for Entrepreneurship and Technology</a>. I&rsquo;ve definitely been thinking in the past few weeks about how we can take this idea to the rest of the world, one signup at a time.</p>

<p>In class, we&rsquo;ve had industry big shots come in and talk a lot about ideation, marketing, distribution strategies, acquiring funding and the like. It&rsquo;s been an eye-opening whirlwind of learning for me.</p>

<p>And even though all this talk about starting a business is dandy, I can&rsquo;t help but feel this greater desire to <em>build something really sweet</em>. Today we had <a href="http://www.pbwiki.com">PBWiki</a> founder David Weekly in class talking about his experience starting the project on his own. And if you&rsquo;ve heard it once, you need to hear it again: <em>It doesn&rsquo;t matter how cool your technology is. All that matters is that you can solve somebody&rsquo;s problem, really really well.</em></p>

<p>So let&rsquo;s do that. After staying dormant for a while, we think it&rsquo;s time to keep Wejoinin moving forward. Last month, we added a friend and developer <a href="http://www.phase-4.org">Jason Ting</a> (of <a href="http://www.iphonesender.com">iPhoneSender</a> fame) to the team. We think he&rsquo;s got a lot of programming and design experience to contribute to the project. We&rsquo;ll have him in here in a little bit to say hi.</p>

<p>Hsiu-Fan and I will drop in here when we have some breathing room to get the rest of this site up and running. Until then, you could do us a great favor by making yourself a sheet and tell us how it&rsquo;s working for you.</p>

<p>Until next time,</p>

<p>-Andrew</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
