<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Design | Wejoinin Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://porkbuns.github.io/blog/blog/categories/design/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://porkbuns.github.io/blog/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-07T21:00:37-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://porkbuns.github.io/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Porkbuns Initiative]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New features released this week!]]></title>
    <link href="http://porkbuns.github.io/blog/2008/11/06/new-features-released-this-week/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-06T13:20:25-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://porkbuns.github.io/blog/2008/11/06/new-features-released-this-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone, I&rsquo;m excited to introduce a couple of new features we&rsquo;ve released this week for you all:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Public sheet list views &amp; custom usernames</p></li>
<li><p>Collapsible sheet sidebars</p></li>
<li><p>Redesigned sheet list home</p></li>
<li><p>New sheet administration options: copy &amp; clear</p></li>
<li><p>Sleeker cell header editing</p></li>
</ul>


<h3>Public sheet list views &amp; custom usernames</h3>

<p>Many sheet creators have requested a way to get people to view a grand, big list of their sheets, all in one place. For example, we&rsquo;ve had requests from professors who want their students to see all of their office hour signup sheets in one place. We&rsquo;ve responded by giving you public sheet lists and custom usernames in your URLs.</p>

<p>How does this work? First, <strong>every user receives an autogenerated custom URL</strong> You can see what it is by logging in and checking the URL location bar in your browser.</p>

<p><a href="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/sheet_list_home1.PNG"><img src="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/sheet_list_home1.thumbnail.PNG" alt="sheet_list_home1.PNG" /></a></p>

<p>A close-up of my location bar:</p>

<p><img src="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/custom_url.PNG" alt="custom_url.PNG" /></p>

<p>Tell all your users to go to this URL, and they&rsquo;ll see a special publicly-visible view of all your sheets:</p>

<p><a href="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/public_sheet_list_view1.PNG"><img src="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/public_sheet_list_view1.thumbnail.PNG" alt="public_sheet_list_view1.PNG" /></a></p>

<p>Of course, if you don&rsquo;t want users to see this list of sheets, you&rsquo;re under no obligation to give out your link. (And yes, we&rsquo;re thinking about building in privacy features so you can choose not to display certain sheets in this view!).</p>

<p>If you want to change your username, you can visit the &ldquo;Account&rdquo; tab and change it:</p>

<p><img src="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/account_username_change.PNG" alt="account_username_change.PNG" /></p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Collapsible sheet sidebars</h3>

<p>Many of you have very, very wide sheets that just don&rsquo;t quite seem to fit on a single page. We&rsquo;ve given you the option to collapse that right sidebar&mdash;goodbye, pesky boxes! Ah, now to stretch our legs&hellip;</p>

<p><a href="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/pre_collapse_highlight1.PNG"><img src="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/pre_collapse_highlight1.thumbnail.PNG" alt="pre_collapse_highlight1.PNG" /></a></p>

<p><a href="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/post_collapse1.PNG"><img src="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/post_collapse1.thumbnail.PNG" alt="post_collapse1.PNG" /></a></p>

<h3>Redesigned sheet list home</h3>

<p>We&rsquo;ve rearranged the look and feel of the buttons on the sheets on the front page, to give some more space for sheet descriptions, and also make some more room for current and future feature releases!</p>

<p><a href="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/sheet_list_home1.PNG"><img src="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/sheet_list_home1.thumbnail.PNG" alt="sheet_list_home1.PNG" /></a></p>

<h3>New sheet administration options: copy &amp; clear</h3>

<p>We&rsquo;ve added the ability for you to copy &amp; clear sheets: take a look!</p>

<p><img src="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/admin_tab.PNG" alt="admin_tab.PNG" /></p>

<p>By <strong>making a copy</strong> of a sheet, you&rsquo;ve made a structural copy of your current sheet for future editing. We can see this particularly useful for those of you who use the same signup sheet for repeating events.</p>

<p>By <strong>clearing a sheet</strong>, you remove all signups from a sheet, keeping all the signup slots. This can be particularly useful if you want to reset or reuse a sheet for another time.</p>

<h3>Sleeker cell header editing</h3>

<p>Finally, we&rsquo;ve made cell editing a whole lot sleeker. You&rsquo;ve now got a lot more room to type out what you need, without the clutter of the previous interface.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/edit_col_header.PNG" alt="edit_col_header.PNG" /></p>

<p><img src="/images/2008-11-06-new-features-released-this-week/edit_row_header.PNG" alt="edit_row_header.PNG" /></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re really excited to hear what you think! If you run into any problems or have any questions or comments, please email <a href="mailto:andrew@wejoinin.com">Andrew</a> or <a href="mailto:hsiufan@wejoinin.com">Hsiu-Fan</a> with what you think!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why go fluid?]]></title>
    <link href="http://porkbuns.github.io/blog/2007/08/16/why-go-fluid/"/>
    <updated>2007-08-16T17:23:30-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://porkbuns.github.io/blog/2007/08/16/why-go-fluid</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of our design decisions was to go with a fluid layout. This meant that the main content was going to expand horizontally with the browser</p>

<p>We noticed quite a few folks using layouts with multiple columns. And as we know, those columns get darn unwieldy when you try to stuff more than three. With a fixed layout, the columns were suffocating the cell content</p>

<p>So we decided to design for those of you with high resolutions (greater than 1024x768) and let you guys put that extra screen width to use.</p>

<p>A very interesting point: the fluid layout, when it becomes too wide, makes text nearly unreadable (longer lines of text increase visual complexity) and single-column tables, well, awkward. We had tossed around ideas of single-column signup sheets staying in a fixed-width layout, then going into an elastic layout once the layout exceeded <em>x</em> number of columns</p>

<p>With design, there&rsquo;s always a tradeoff. Man.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A brief history of how we were born!]]></title>
    <link href="http://porkbuns.github.io/blog/2007/06/09/a-brief-history-of-how-we-were-born/"/>
    <updated>2007-06-09T07:59:48-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://porkbuns.github.io/blog/2007/06/09/a-brief-history-of-how-we-were-born</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4>How we were born!</h4>

<p>Wejoinin, as most Web applications go, was borne as a solution to a real-world problem. Late in 2006, I was in a meeting with leaders from a few of the Christian fellowships at UC Berkeley planning a prayer vigil. We realized that we needed a way to track people coming.</p>

<p>&ldquo;We need an online signup sheet,&rdquo; somebody said. &ldquo;Preferably by tomorrow.&rdquo; Then I felt all the eyes in the room fall on me.</p>

<p>Crap.</p>

<p>I went back to my apartment and slapped together a PHP script with the help of my friend Ryan. That night, a fairly crippled script flew on tattered wings.</p>

<p>But the important thing was that it worked. We got some positive and constructive feedback from a bunch of folks. And over the next few months, we lovingly reworked the code. We fussed with the UI. We added some helpful AJAX dialogs (even if the buzzword <em>was</em> a bit tacky).</p>

<p>Soon more and more folks requested the code for their own prayer rooms. And as this whole thing started blowing up in popularity, a few of our friends suggested that we make this a hosted service. And we open it up to all sorts of signups. And we get a cool glossy reflective logo (just kidding, we heard you gagging).</p>

<h4>On a wing and a prayer</h4>

<p>It happened that summer I was interning at a <a href="http://www.faqqly.com">certain special startup</a> with my friend and classmate, Hsiu-fan. Hsiu-fan had been giving me helpful critiques and suggestions with regards to the signup page, and he had downright ninja skills when it came to code. Well that summer we had been playing in Ruby on Rails and we figured, why not, let&rsquo;s code this thing in RoR like all the cool kids do.</p>

<p>We tossed a few ideas around and came up with Wejoinin, the online signup sheet that doesn&rsquo;t make you cry. And by not making you cry, we mean we really wanted to come up with a signup sheet service so easy your mother could use and so awesome your geeky cousin rocking a Twitter shirt could gush about&hellip;</p>

<p>(more to come!)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
